# MATTHIAS QUINN

### DATA ANALYST



(330) 741-1068



miq\_qedquinn@yahoo.com



Brunswick, OH 44212



**GitHub** 

## **Executive Summary**

I am an analytically minded developer with 5 years of experience in data analysis and 2 years of experience in model building. I hold a Master of Science in mathematics with a specialization in statistics where I created software in Python for analyzing the validity of clustering models.

## **Experience**

Jul 2021 - Present

#### **DATA ANALYST**

Progressive Insurance, Mayfield, OH

- Applied modern design to businessfacing analytics solutions.
- Reviewed large amounts of data across multiple platforms and sources to determine operational impacts and needed actions.
- Developed and modeled internal metrics using SQL, Python, Tableau, and PowerBI.
- Extracted key observations and insights from internal and external data sources to drive decision-making.

Aug 2019 - Dec 2021

#### **GRADUATE ASSISTANT**

Cleveland State University, Cleveland, OH

- Provided walk-in tutoring for statistics courses at all levels at C.S.U.
- Utilized different teaching strategies to best assist student clientele.

May 2020 - Jul 2020

#### RESEARCH ASSISTANT

Cleveland State University, Cleveland, OH

#### Education

#### **Dec 2021**

## **MASTER OF SCIENCE** (M.S.) IN STATISTICS

GPA **4.0** 

Cleveland State University Cleveland, OH

#### **Awards & Honors**

Graduate Assistantship

## Extracurricular **Activities**

Math Club Data Fest

## May 2019

## **BACHELOR OF ARTS** (B.A.) IN FINANCE

Cleveland State University Cleveland, OH

#### **Awards & Honors**

Dean's List

- Analyzed the ADD Health database.
- Created hierarchical / SEM models to identify at-risk youth.

## Skills

Data Analysis

SQL

• Machine Learning

Python

• F

• Data Visualization

MS Office

• Tableau

SAS

## **Publications**

Explaining the school-to-prison pipeline via race and gender: The impact of trauma, school suspension, school dropout, and delinquency – Tedor, Mallett, Quinn, Quinn

Examining Trauma and Crime by Gender and Sexual Orientation among Youth: Findings from the Add Health National Longitudinal Study – Yun, Tedor, Mallett, Quinn, Quinn